Guide to the Barry Gifford Papers M0927
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 2. Manuscripts
  - Wild at Heart: The Story of Sailor and Lula: Original manuscript [1 of 8], undated (Box 32, Folder 12)
    TMs, TMs (photocopy), AMs, 20 pp.
  - Wild at Heart: The Story of Sailor and Lula: Original manuscript [2 of 8], undated (Box 32, Folder 13)
    AMs with TMs, 50 pp.
  - Wild at Heart: The Story of Sailor and Lula: Original manuscript [3 of 8], undated (Box 32, Folder 14)
    AMs with TMs, 52 pp.
  - Wild at Heart: The Story of Sailor and Lula: Original manuscript [4 of 8], undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
    AMs with TMs, 60 pp.
  - Wild at Heart: The Story of Sailor and Lula: Original manuscript [5 of 8], undated (Box 32, Folder 16)
    TMs with holographic notes, 48 pp.
  - Wild at Heart: The Story of Sailor and Lula: Original manuscript [6of 8], undated (Box 32, Folder 17)
    TMs with holographic notes, 50 pp.
  - Wild at Heart: The Story of Sailor and Lula: Original manuscript [7 of 8], undated (Box 32, Folder 18)
    TMs with holographic notes, 49 pp.
  - Wild at Heart: The Story of Sailor and Lula: Original manuscript [8 of 8], undated (Box 33, Folder 1)
    TMs with holographic notes, 36pp.
  - The Yellow Palace, undated (Box 33, Folder 2)
    AMs 12 pp
  - Dawson, Fielding: "Leo 1675", undated (Box 33, Folder 3)
    TMs 28 pp
  - Nelson, Kent: "The Straight Man" [1 of 2], undated (Box 33, Folder 4)
    TMs 60 pp
  - Nelson, Kent: "The Straight Man" [2 of 2], undated (Box 33, Folder 5)
    TMs 61 pp
  - Beautiful Phantoms: Poems 1968-1980: galley proofs, 1981 June 1 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    TMs, 38 pp.
  - The Boy You Have Always Loved: Poems 1967-1976: galley proofs, undated (Box 48, Folder 3)
    TMs, 11 pp.; 1 ALS
  - Francis goes to the seashore: the second pillow book of Francis Reeves, undated (Box 48, Folder 4)
    AMs and TMs with holographic notes, 65 pp.; 2 ANS
  - The Nosferatu Papers; with woodcuts by Adrian Goldsmith, undated (Box 48, Folder 5)
    TMs, ca. 20 pp. [NOTE: This file is currently unavailable pending restoration and conservation]
  - The Book of the Poet's Myth, 1970 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    AMs, 71 pp.
  - The Nosferatu Papers with woodcuts by Adrian Goldsmith: mock up, 1967 (Box 49, Folder 2)
    {NOTE: This file is currently unavailable pending restoration and conservation]
- Series 3. Notebooks
  - Notebook 1, undated (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Notebook 2, undated (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Notebook 3: Tessai Poem, undated (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Notebook 4: Berkeley 1967 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Notebook 5, undated (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Notebook 6: Trail to New Mexico, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Notebook 7: Travel Journal: Frisco - Illinois, 1968 (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Notebook 8: Journal written in the Woods, London Journal, 1969 (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Notebook 9: Canada Trip, 1970 Feb (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Notebook 10: Trail to Albuquerque, undated (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Notebook 11: Coyote Book, undated (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Notebook 12, undated (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Notebook 13: The Boy You Have Always Loved, undated (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Notebook 14: Trailbook, undated (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Notebook 15, undated (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Notebook 16, circa 1970 (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Notebook 17: No Enemy of Horses, undated (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Notebook 18: Very Truly Yours, undated (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Notebook 19, undated (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Notebook 20: Persimmons Poems for Paintings, undated (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Notebook 21: Persimmons Poems, Trip to Lowell, Tantras, et al., undated (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Notebook 22: A Boy's Novel, parts two, three and four, undated (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Notebook 23: Eppa Pilot's Travels, etc., undated (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Notebook 24: Adios Dream, undated (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Notebook 25: Hobo Bill, The Duke of Earl's Court, Adios Dream, undated (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Notebook 26: Hevajra - Tantra Notes - Late Rain, undated (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Notebook 27: The Horse in the Field, undated (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Notebook 28: De Angulo article, undated (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - Ahetenrai, undated (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - Buddies, Big Steve at the Convention..., undated (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Colby College, undated (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - A Day at the Races, undated (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Dec. '77 -1978, 1977 -1978 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Denver - Boulder, 1976 -1977 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - The Devil Thumbs a Ride and other unforgettable films, undated (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Dixie Peach, undated (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Dixie Slattery, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - An Eye on the Alligators, undated (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Florida: The Isle of Flowers, undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Francis Goes to the Seashore: The Second Pillow Book of Francis Jammes, undated (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - A Good Man to Know: New York and Florida, 1981 -1983 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Horse in the Field, undated (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Japan, 1975 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Key West, undated (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Landscape with Traveler: Landscape - First Draft, undated (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - M Notes [Landscape with Traveler] New York, 1977 Feb-Nov (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Murder at the Swordfish Club, undated (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - Nadja in Paradise, undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - The Neighborhood of Baseball: A Personal History of Chicago and the Cubs, book one, undated (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - The Neighborhood of Baseball: A Personal History of Chicago and the Cubs, part two, undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - New York - Berkeley, 1975 (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - New Zealand: In the land of the long white cloud, undated (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Night People: Duke - Edwards 1991, Mississippi Journal 1992, 1991 -1992 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Paris, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Paris - Venice - London - New York, 1982 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Paris - London - New York, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Poems from Snail Hut, undated (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Port Tropique: Berkeley, Mérida, undated (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Riffraff, undated (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Sailor's Holiday / Wild at Heart and poems, circa 1988 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Tokyo - Kyoto - Sapporo / Asahigawa - Hokkaido, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 1)
  - Tokyo - Mt. Yatsu - L.A. - New York - Philadelphia, undated (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - The train to Baltimore, undated (Box 40, Folder 3)
  - The Tunisian Notebook of August Macke, 1979, Baseball 1980, 1979 -1980 (Box 40, Folder 4)
  - Uncle Buck and other stories, undated (Box 40, Folder 5)
  - Vancouver - Haney, British Columbia, 1970 Feb (Box 40, Folder 6)
  - A Year in the Life, undated (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Untitled memobook [on Florida], undated (Box 40, Folder 8)
  - Untitled memobook [Landscape with Travelers], undated (Box 40, Folder 9)
  - Untitled memobook [Pilgrim Chant / Cerebral Observations, part II], undated (Box 40, Folder 10)
  - Untitled notebook [Trip to Japan], undated (Box 40, Folder 11)
  - Tablet with poems, undated (Box 48, Folder 6)
  - Tablet with poems, undated (Box 48, Folder 7)
    AMs, 4 pp.; TMs, 2 pp.
- Series 4. Audiovisual Materials
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Bassett, Lafe [1 of 3], undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
    1 audiocassette
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Bassett, Lafe [2 of 3], undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Bassett, Lafe [3 of 3], undated (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Bassett, Lafe [1 of 3], undated (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Bassett, Lafe [2 of 3], undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Bassett, Lafe [3 of 3], undated (Box 41, Folder 6)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Capp, Timothy T., undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Cooper, Bryson, undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Gaines, John R., undated (Box 41, Folder 9)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Gibson, John, undated (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Lundberg, Liz, undated (Box 41, Folder 11)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Prospero, Floyd [1 of 3], undated (Box 41, Folder 12)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Prospero, Floyd [2 of 3], undated (Box 41, Folder 13)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Prospero, Floyd [3 of 3], undated (Box 41, Folder 14)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Prospero, Floyd [1 of 4], undated (Box 41, Folder 15)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Prospero, Floyd [2 of 4], undated (Box 41, Folder 16)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Prospero, Floyd [3 of 4], undated (Box 41, Folder 17)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Prospero, Floyd [4 of 4], undated (Box 41, Folder 18)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Robinson, Art, undated (Box 41, Folder 19)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Santos, Joe, undated (Box 41, Folder 20)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Somers, Richard [1 of 3], undated (Box 41, Folder 21)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Somers, Richard [2 of 3], undated (Box 41, Folder 22)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Somers, Richard [3 of 3], undated (Box 41, Folder 23)
  - A Day at the Races: Interview with Tumwater Tom, Barbara Hagen, Paul Fisher, undated (Box 41, Folder 24)
  - The State of Florida: Interview with Davey, Ross, undated (Box 41, Folder 25)
  - The State of Florida: Interview with Harry, Elwood, Vic Dunaway, Greg McIntosh, Clint Allen, and Rick Allen, undated (Box 41, Folder 26)
  - The State of Florida: Interview with Harry, E.K. and Mike Leech, undated (Box 41, Folder 27)
  - The State of Florida: Interview with Johnson, Jay, undated (Box 41, Folder 28)
  - The State of Florida: Interview with McIntosh, Greg, undated (Box 41, Folder 29)
  - The State of Florida: Interview with Storer, Sandy and Jack Coleman, undated (Box 41, Folder 30)
  - The State of Florida: Interview with Wheland, Charlie and Allen Merritt, undated (Box 41, Folder 31)
- Series 5. Publications
  - a. Pamphlets
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. The blood of the parade, and other poems, 1965-1967 / by Barry Gifford. [London: s.n.], c1967. [2], 46 p.; 21 cm. (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. Chinese Notes. Berkeley: Donald S. Ellis, 1980 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. From Persimmons / Barry Gifford. Brunswick, Me.: Blackberry, c1974. [16] p.; 22 cm. Blackberry 4. (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. From Persimmons / Barry Gifford. Brunswick, Me.: Blackberry, c1974. [16] p.; 22 cm. Blackberry 4. (Box 42, Folder 4)
      signed
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. The last lunchcart Christmas / Barry Gifford. [s.l.: s.n.], 1973. [8] p.; 22 cm. (Box 42, Folder 5)
      2 copies
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. Letters to Proust / Barry Gifford. Buffalo, N. Y.: White Pine, c1976. [20] p.: ill.; 22 cm. White pine; 4 (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. Lives of the French Impressionist Painters. Berkeley: Donald S. Ellis, 1978 (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. Nadja in Paradise. Petaluma, CA: Ten Mile River Press, 1984 (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. [Jammes, Francis, 1868-1938.] The naked girl: a poem/play / by Francis Jammes; translated by Barry Gifford and Bettina Dickie. Berkeley, Calif.: Workingmans Press, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. Persimmons: poems for paintings / Barry Gifford. Berkeley: Shaman Drum, 1977. [54] p.; 18 cm. (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. Poems from snail hut / Barry Gifford. Santa Barbara, Calif.: Christopher Books, 1978, c1977. [32] p.; 23 cm. (Box 42, Folder 11)
      Paperbound in white; printed and illustrated in blue and red-orange; burnt orange endpapers.
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. The prayer of the star route. New York, Oliphant Press,1971. [4] p. (on double leaves) 21 cm. (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. A quinzaine in return for a portrait of Mary Sun / Barry Gifford. Berkeley: The Workingmans Press, 1977. [20] p.; 22 cm. (Box 42, Folder 13)
      Paperbound in white; printed in yellow, brown-red and black.
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. The Tunisian notebook / by Barry Gifford. Fort Bragg, Calif.: Ten Mile River Press, c1983. [32] p.: port.; 22 cm. (Box 42, Folder 14)
      Paperbound in white; printed in black and maroon; maroon endpapers; cover photos. Erratum slips bound in.
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. Uncle Buck / by Barry Gifford. Fort Bragg, Calif.: Ten Mile River Press, c1983. [8], 10, [4] p.; 22 cm. (Box 42, Folder 15)
      Paperbound in white; printed in blue; front cover photo and rear cover photo of the author.
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. The Way to be with Women. Berkeley: Creative Arts Printing / Book Company, 1979 (Box 42, Folder 16)
    - DeSerio, Vinnie. For Linda. [s.l.]: Madrugada Press, undated (Box 42, Folder 17)
      ANS
    - Woodward, Dewing. The Mass of the Shepherds of Province. Woodstock, NY: The Maverick Press, 1911 (Box 42, Folder 18)
  - b. Broadsides
    - Gifford, Barry. The Surrealists come to California. Berkeley: Hormone Derange Editions, Last Chance Gulch (Peter Rutledge Koch, printer)., 1996 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      [1 of 100, signed]
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. At an exhibition of scrolls & drawings by Tomioka Tessai: 2nd of December 1968. [Berkeley]: Shaman Drum Broadside, no. 1, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 19)
      signed by the author
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. At an exhibition of scrolls & drawings by Tomioka Tessai: 2nd of December 1968. [Berkeley]: Shaman Drum Broadside, no. 1, 1977 (Box 42, Folder 20)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. The Giants are going to win the pennant / by Barry Gifford. [Westport, CA: Madrugada, 1971?] Madrugada broadside (Box 42, Folder 21)
      3 broadsides; 18 x 26 cm. Orange paper printed in black.
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. Ode to John Garfield / Barry Gifford. San Francisco: Madrugada, c1972. folder (4 p.): port.; 23 cm. A Madrugada broadside. (Box 42, Folder 22)
      "this is number 25 of 100 copies, 26 of which are signed by the author." Signed by the author
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. Phoebe. [s.l.: s.n.], undated circa 1976? (Box 42, Folder 23)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. Song. [s.l.]: White Pine Press, 1975 (Box 42, Folder 24)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. Tear the stars down from the sky. [s.l.]: White Pine Press, 1975 (Box 42, Folder 25)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. Twelfth Street. [s.l.: s.n.], undated (Box 42, Folder 26)
    - Gifford, Barry, 1946-. World of our Fathers [s.l.: s.n.], 1977 Aug 6 (Box 42, Folder 27)
    - BigEagle, Duane. Bidato (October Pomo Village) / by Duane Big Eagle. [Berkeley, Calif.: Workingmans Press?], [1975] (Box 42, Folder 28)
      broadside; 26 x 15 cm. 2 copies. ANS
  - c. Literary Journals
    - Journal 31.--Vol. 1, no. 1, 1972 Summer (Box 42, Folder 29)
      includes: Coyote Tantras XXXVIII, LXIX, LXXXII, CXXXII ANS
    - The Lampeter muse [Annandale-on-Hudson, N.Y., Bard College.].--Vol. 6, no. 1, 1971 Fall -Winter (Box 42, Folder 30)
      includes: poems from Coyote Tantras, pp. 51 -57 ALS
    - Madrugada. [Westport, Calif., Madrugada Press].--No. 2 [1 of 3], 1971 (Box 42, Folder 31)
    - Madrugada. [Westport, Calif., Madrugada Press].--No. 2 [2 of 3], 1971 (Box 42, Folder 32)
    - Madrugada. [Westport, Calif., Madrugada Press].--No. 2 [3 of 3], 1971 (Box 42, Folder 33)
    - Madrugada. [Westport, Calif., Madrugada Press].--No. 2 [1 of 3], 1971 (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Madrugada. [Westport, Calif., Madrugada Press].--No. 2 [2 of 3], 1971 (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Madrugada. [Westport, Calif., Madrugada Press].--No. 2 [3 of 3], 1971 (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Road apple review. [Oshkosh, Wisc., Road Runner Press].--Vol. 3, nos. 2 - 3, 1971 Summer -Fall (Box 43, Folder 4)
      "William Everson double issue" includes: Coyote Tantra, p. 48 -50 1 TLS
    - San Francisco Review of Books.--Vol. 6, no. 3, 1980 Nov-Dec (Box 43, Folder 5)
      includes: Nowicki, Ron. "Interview with Barry Gifford," pp. 6ff.
    - Truck.--No. 9, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 6)
      includes: "Trip to Lowell," pp. 19 -25 ANS
  - d. Magazines
    - Angler's Digest: Official Yearbook of the Bay of Islands Swordfish Club, Inc., 1987 -1988 (Box 43, Folder 7)
      includes research materials for "The State of Florida"
    - Club Yearbook: Bay of Islands Swordfish Club, Inc., 1984 (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Condé Nast Traveler.--Vol. 23, no. 1, 1988 Jan (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Hawaiian Charter Fishing Guide.--Vol. 8, no. 12, 1987 Dec (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - The International Angler.--Vol. 49, no. 6, 1987 Nov-Dec (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Marlin: The Magazine of Big Game Fishing.--Vol. 6, no. 6, 1987 Dec-1988 Jan (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Marlin: The Magazine of Big Game Fishing.--Vol. 7, no. 1, 1988 Feb-Mar (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Marlin: The Magazine of Big Game Fishing.--Vol. 7, no. 2, 1988 Apr-May (Box 43, Folder 14)
    - Marlin: The Magazine of Big Game Fishing.--Vol. 7, no. 3, 1988 July (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - South Coast Sportfishing.--Vol. 8, no. 3, 1988 Mar (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Vox Magazine.--Vol. 1, no. 1, 1990 Nov (Box 43, Folder 17)
      includes film review of Wild at Heart, pp. 71 -73
- Series 6. Ephemera
  - David Lynch's Wild at Heart [movie poster], undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Lost Highway [movie poster], undated (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Christopher's Books Catalogue, 1972 Fall -Winter (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Clark City Press Catalog, 1991 Fall -1992 Winter (Box 44, Folder 2)
    includes: New Mysteries of Paris
  - Curtis, Edward S., 1868-1952. The North American Indian: being a series of volumes picturing and describing the Indians of the United States, and Alaska / written, illustrated, and published by Edward S. Curtis; edited by Frederick Webb Hodge; foreword by Theodore Roosevelt; field research conducted under the patronage of J. Pierpont Morgan. [Seattle]: E.S. Curtis; [Cambridge, Mass.: The University Press], 1907. vol. 1: fronts. (v. 18, 20 col.) plates, ports., music 33 cm. (Box 44, Folder 3)
    photocopy with holographic notes
  - The Famous authors calendar. Santa Barbara, [Calif.]: Christopher's Books, [1976]. [12] leaves (in portfolio); 30 cm. (Box 44, Folder 4)
    includes "New? In Transit"
  - Free University of Berkeley: Fall 1968 printed catalog, 1968 Fall (Box 44, Folder 5)
    4to, wrs.
  - Harcourt Brace & Company: Adult Hardcover Books [catalog], 1995 -1996 (Box 44, Folder 6)
  - Program for "An Evening Honoring Claire Bloom" Lincoln Center, 1982 Feb 18 (Box 44, Folder 7)
  - Random Writers, undated (Box 44, Folder 8)
    advance notice for Sailor's Holiday
  - San Francisco Chronicle: clipping on "Cable's Brand of Film Noir", 1991 Nov 14 (Box 44, Folder 9)
  - Sheet music, undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
    Montemezzi, Italo, 1875-1952. [Amore dei tre re. Libretto. English & Italian] L'amore dei tre re, tragic poem in 3 acts by Sem Benelli; English version by R. H. Elkin, music by Italo Montemezzi. New York, London [etc.] G. Ricordi & co., 1913. 61p. 24cm. [Pelleas et Melisande. Libretto. English & French] Pelleas and Melisande: lyric drama in five acts: taken from the play by Maurice Maeterlinck / music by Claude Debussy; English version by Charles Alfred Byrne. New York: F. Rullman, c1907. 59 p.; 24 cm. On cover: "The only correct and authorized edition." Mascagni, Pietro, 1863-1945. [Cavalleria rusticana. Libretto. English & Italian] Rustic chivalry (Cavalleria rusticana) melodrama in one act ... English version by J. C. Macy. Rustic chivalry (libretto) Cavalleria rusticana (libretto) Boston, O. Ditson co., c1919. 25 p. illus. (music) 25 cm.
  - University Press of Mississippi Publication Catalogue, 1995 Mar (Box 44, Folder 11)
  - University Press of Mississippi Publication Catalogue, 1995 Sep (Box 44, Folder 12)
  - University Press of Mississippi Publication Catalogue, 1996 Mar (Box 44, Folder 13)
  - University Press of Mississippi Publication Catalogue, 1996 Sep (Box 44, Folder 14)
- Series 7. Books
  - a. Books by Others
    - AAA Tourbook: Florida, 1988 (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Anderson, Robert. Guide to Florida Salt Water Fishing. [s.l.]: Winner Enterprises, 1984. (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Boese, Kay. Tides of history: Bay of Islands County / by Kay Boese; cover design, sketches and layout advice by Selwyn Wilson. [Whangarei, N.Z.]: Bay of Islands County Council, 1977. 470 p.: ill.; 30 cm. (Box 45, Folder 3)
    - Field guide to saltwater fishes of North America McClane's Field guide to saltwater fishes of North America: a project of the Gamefish Research Association / Field guide to saltwater fishes of North America. Edited by A. J. McClane; ill. by Frances Watkins and Richard E. Younger. New York: Holt, Rinehart and Winston, c1978. xviii, 283 p.: col. ill.; 21 cm. [Portions originally published in McClane's standard fishing encyclopedia and international angling guide (1965) and McClane's new standard fishing encyclopedia and international angling guide (1974). Includes index.] (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Forsyth, Frederick, 1938-. No comebacks: collected short stories / Frederick Forsyth. New York: Bantam Books, 1982. 290 p. (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Hansen, Elizabeth, 1945-. Bed and breakfast New Zealand / by Elizabeth Hansen. San Francisco: Chronicle Books, c1987. 230 p.: ill.; 22 cm. (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Hersey, John, 1914-. Blues / John Hersey; with drawings by James Baker. New York: Vintage Books, 1988, c1987. 205 p.: ill.; 21 cm. (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - King, Jane, 1956-. New Zealand handbook / Jane King. 1st ed. Chico, Calif., USA: Moon Publications, c1987. 503 p., [8] p. of plates: ill., (some col.) maps, ports.; 19 cm. (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - McClane, A. J. (Albert Jules), 1922- [Secrets of successful fishing] McClane's Secrets of successful fishing / A. J. McClane. Secrets of successful fishing. 1st ed. New York: Holt, Rinehart and Winston, 1980, c1979. xii, 276 p.: ill.; 21 cm. [Based on McClane's New standard fishing encyclopedia. Includes index. Bibliography: p. 267-268.] (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - New Zealand / edited by Gordon McLauchlan; photographed by Max Lawrence; directed and designed by Hans Johannes Hoefer. 2nd ed. Singapore: APA Productions; New York, N.Y.: Prentice-Hall Press, 1986. 339 p.: ill. (some col.); 23 cm. (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Ross, James, 1911-. They don't dance much. New York: Signet, 1940. [6], 296 p.; 21 cm. (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Underwood, John, 1934-. Ted Williams fishing "the big three": tarpon, bonefish, Atlantic salmon / by John Underwood and Ted Williams. New York: Simon and Schuster, c1982. 151 p.: ill.; 24 cm. (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Walton, Izaak, 1593-1683. The compleat angler / Izaak Walton; edited by Bryan Loughrey; with a postscript by Lord Home. Harmondsworth, England; New York: Penguin, 1985. 149 p.: ill.; 20 cm. (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Whalen, Philip. Off the wall: interviews with Philip Whalen / edited by Donald Allen. Bolinas, Calif.: Four Seasons Foundation, c1978. 88 p.; 22 cm. [Contents: A short chronology--Tiger whiskers: interview with Anne Waldman (1971).--Interview with Aram Saroyan (1972).--Zen poet: interview with Yves Le Pellec (1972).--Interview with Lee Bartlett (1975).--Remembering Jack Kerouac, with Barry Gifford and Larry Lee (1976). ISBN: 0877040354. 0877040362 pbk.: $3.50 (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Wheeler, Tony. New Zealand, a travel survival kit / [Tom Wheeler]. 4th ed. South Yarra, Vic.; Berkeley, Calif.: Lonely Planet, 1985. 247 p.: ill.; 19 cm. (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - World record game fishes. World record game fishes 1987 edition [Fort Lauderdale, Fla.] International Game Fish Association, 1987. 320 p. v. ill. 26 cm. (Box 47, Folder 2)
- Series 8. Accession 2013-023: Manuscripts for 9 Books
  - The Stars Above Veracruz (Box 1, Folders 1-5)
  - The Stars Above Veracruz: manuscript (Box 1, Folders 6-8)
  - The Stars Above Veracruz: manuscript (Box 1, Folders 9-11)